A Guide to the Papers of John F. Greenlee and the Greenlee family 1858-1898
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of John F. Greenlee and the Greenlee family 1858-1898
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
5213-c
This collection consists of 600 items.
Administrative Information
Access
There are no restrictions.
Scope and Content Information
The papers chiefly contain receipts and financial and legal instruments of John F. Greenlee, including a county tax book; a fee book, 1859-1861; and pocket account books. There is miscellaneous material regarding taxes and tax sales and also regarding a Lynchburg, Va., circuit court, 1860.
Additional Descriptive Data
Separated Material
1832, Fourth Report of the American Temperance Society, 1 vol.
n.d., Treatise on Soils and Manures, 1 vol.
Contents List
- Court summons for Samuel Vanderslice, signed by William Dodd [1819] November 5, 1 p. (Box 1)
- Account of John Shorte 1828-1829, 1 item (Box 1)
- Papers concerning the settlement of the estate of Joseph Gilmore 1829-1862, 15 pp. (Box 1)
- Receipts and land papers and will of David Greenlee 1834-1882, 15 items (Box 1)
- Will of James Jordan 1835 April 2, 1 item (Box 1)
- Papers of settlement of Joseph Gilmore with Jo Humes for Humes Heirs 1839-1863, ca. 100 items (Box 1)
- Wm. Humes to Joseph Gilmore 1845 August 6 and September 5 (Box 2 ALS, 5 pp.)
- E. S. Humes to Joseph Gilmore 1849 December 30, ALS, 3 pp. (Box 1)
- Expense book of [John F. Greenlee] mostly blank ca. 1850, w/7 misc. loose items (Box 1)
- Papers concerning estate of David Greenlee 1850-1872, ca. 50 items (Box 1)
- Miscellaneous lists of licenses, tickets and receipts, Rockbridge County 1855-1878, ca. 80 items (Box 1)
- Envelope addressed to John H. Cocke, postmarked "University of VA." 1857 September 24, 1 p. (Box 1)
- Papers concerning the settlement of the estate of Joseph Gilmore 1857-1865, ca. 35 items (Box 1)
- List of Insolvent Taxes, Rockbridge County 1858, 6 pp. (Box 1)
- Liscense Receipts for Rockbridge County 1858-1862, 43 pp. (Box 1)
- Settlement of the estate of Mrs. Eliza W. Paxton 1858-1865, 45 items (Box 1)
- Miscellaneous Bonds, Bills of Sale, Rockbridge County 1858-1865, ca. 100 items (Box 1)
- Papers Relating to Settlement of Debt of J.R. Saunders and J.W. Eads to Issac Burkholder 1859, 8 items (Box 1)
- Miscellaneous Receipts and Papers, Rockbridge County 1859, 8 items (Box 1)
- Receipts of Rockbridge County Allowances 1859, 55 items (Box 1)
- Jury Allowances, Rockbridge County 1859, 1 item (Box 1)
- List of Jurors for Circuit Court 1859, 1 item (Box 1)
- Receipts of Miscellaneous Taxes paid Rockbridge County 1859, 15 items (Box 1)
- Receipts of John F. Greenlee 1859, 40 items (Box 1)
- Various Tax Receipts, Rockbridge County 1859, 44 items (Box 1)
- Small booklet containing list of proper names, concerning a poll vote taken at Natural Bridge, Va. for Governor 1859, 15 pp. (Box 1)
- Jonathan Shafer to John Greenlee [1859], ALS, 1 p. (Box 1)
- Deed to land of J.R. Greenlee 1859 January 31, 2 pp. (Box 1)
- I.B. Wilson to the Sheriff of Rockbridge County1859 April 19, ALS, 1 p. (Box 1)
- Lists of Militia Fines, Rockbridge County 1859-1860, 4 items (Box 1)
- Receipts of Rockbridge County Allowances 1859-1860, 88 items (Box 1)
- Militia Fines, Miscellaneous Bonds and various receipts for Rockbridge County 1859-1860 (Box 15 items)
- Rockbridge County Receipts 1859-1860, 25 items (Box 1)
- Insolvent Tax List 1859-1862, 11 items (Box 2)
- Receipts of Taxes paid in Rockbridge County 1859-1863, 29 items (Box 2)
- Expense books of John F. Greenlee 1859-1864, 5 items w/misc. loose pieces (Box 2)
- Fee book of John F. Greenlee 1859-1865, 105 pp. (Box 2)
- Miscellaneous legal papers (deeds, etc) 1859-1892, 13 items (Box 2)
- List of allowances for Rockbridge County 1860, 1 item (Box 2)
- Receipts of miscellaneous taxes paid Rockbridge County 1860, 10 items (Box 2)
- List of Delinquents South Western District, Rockbridge County 1860, 3 items (Box 2)
- Rules of the County Court of Rockbridge 1860, 1 item (Box 2)
- Receipts of John F. Greenlee 1860, 56 items (Box 2)
- Miscellaneous receipts and papers, Rockbridge County 1860, 6 items (Box 2)
- Accounts of Mrs. John F. Greenlee 1860, 10 items (Box 2)
- Miscellaneous receipts to John F. Greenlee, Deputy Sheriff 1860, 10 items (Box 2)
- [?] D. Christian to [John] Greenlee 1860 February 17, ALS, 1 p. (Box 2)
- Lucien H. Thompson to John H. Greenlee 1860 May 5, ALS, 1 p. (Box 2)
- Edmund Fitzgerald to [John Greenlee] 1860 November 22, ALS, 1 p. (Box 2)
- Sam H. Quaile to [John Greelee] 1860 December 20, ALS, 1 p. (Box 2)
- G.W. Manly to Watson and [John] Greenlee 1860 December 23, ALS, 1 p. (Box 2)
- List of Free Negroes in Rockbridge County 1860, 1 item (Box 2)
- Various Tax Receipts, Rockbridge County 1860-1861, 68 items (Box 2)
- Miscellaneous receipts and papers, Rockbridge County 1860-1862, 10 items (Box 2)
- Settlement of all claims between the estates of Joseph Gilmore and Eliza Humes 1860-1876, 8 items (Box 2)
- Various tax receipts, Rockbridge County 1861, 50 items (Box 2)
- Commonwealth vs Rapp and Hartsook, account paper 1861, 1 item (Box 2)
- Receipts of John F. Greenlee 1861, ca. 80 items (Box 2)
- Accounts of Mrs. John F. Greenlee 1861, 17 items (Box 2)
- Statements and Settlements of Taxes, Rockbridge County 1861-1862, 21 items (Box 2)
- Receipts of Rockbridge County Allowances 1861-1862, 56 items (Box 2)
- Papers relating to settlement of estate of P.A. Sallings; John F. Greenlee, Adm. 1861-1871, 18 items (Box 2)
- Accounts of Mrs. John F. Greenlee 1862, 9 items (Box 2)
- Various tax receipts, Rockbridge County 1862, 19 items (Box 2)
- Copy of Sale Bill of Estate of Polly Bailey 1862, 1 item (Box 2)
- Receipts of John F. Greenlee 1862, ca. 75 items (Box 2)
- Agreement between Mrs. Greenlee and Eli S. Tutwiler, A.Q.M. for Mrs. Greenlee to keep horses for the C[onfederate] S[tates] 1862 January 2, 1 p. (Box 2)
- Joseph G. Steele to Mrs. H.P. Greenlee 1862 May 12, ALS, 1 p. (Box 2)
- Ro. I. White to Mrs. H. Greenlee 1862 May 18, ALS, 1 p. (Box 2)
- Alexanile (?) Shannon to John Greenlee 1862 May 21, ALS, 1 p. (Box 2)
- Printed oath of allegiance to the Confederate States of America, signed by E.G. Greenlee 1862 July 19, 1 item (Box 2)
- I. and J. Poague and Co. to Mrs. H.J. Greenlee 1862 Aug. 21, ALS, 1 p. (Box 1)
- Wm. P. Bailey to [John F. Greenlee] 1862 October 8, ALS, 3 pp. (Box 2)
- Clifton C. Burks to William W. Boyd 1862 November 27, ALS, 1 p. (Box 2)
- Wm. W. Boyd to John F. Greenlee 1862 December 6, ALS, 1 p. (Box 2)
- Receipts of Rockbridge County Allowances 1862-1863, 37 items (Box 3)
- Broadsides re: sale of property 1862-1866, 4 items (Box 3)
- J.F. Greenlee, Trustee vs. William Paxton and John Poague 1862-1891, 8 items (Box 3)
- W. Harder (?) to John Greenlee [1863], ALS, 1 p. (Box 3)
- Settlement of Estate of Polly Bailey 1863, 6 items (Box 3)
- Various Tax Receipts, Rockbridge County 1863, 43 items (Box 3)
- Will of Joseph Gilmore 1863, copy (Box 3)
- Receipts and Letters concerning Rockbridge Artillery Company 1863, 17 items (Box 3)
- Receipts of John F. Greenlee 1863, 15 items (Box 3)
- Miscellaneous Receipts and Papers, Rockbridge County 1863, 14 items (Box 3)
- Promiscous papers relating to Executions and Settled Memorandums 1863, 20 items (Box 3)
- Canceled Bond, J.S. Greenlee to J.D. Davidson 1863, 4 items (Box 3)
- F.L. Anderson to John F. Greenlee [18]63 February 21, ALS, 2 pp. (Box 3)
- John F. Greenlee to Frederick S. Galloway 1863 March 5, ANS, 1 p. (Box 3)
- John F. Greenlee to John Welcher, to John Sinkerhoker and to F. and M. Guggenheimer 1863 March 5 and 9, 3 ALS, 1 p. each (Box 3)
  each w/2 ANS on back from John G. Watson and James Campbell
- James Paxton to J. Greenlee and Dr. Watson 1863 April 17, ALS, 1 p. (Box 3)
- Virginia F. to Uncle John [Greenlee] 1863 June 26, ALS, 5 pp. (Box 3)
- List of Number of Slaves drafted in Rockbridge County to labor on the Defenses of Richmond 1863 September 22, 1 item (Box 3)
- James S. Greenlee to Dear Cousin1863 October 28, ALS, 2 pp. (Box 3)
- G.W. Hick to John Greenlee 1863 December 24, ALS, 2 pp. (Box 3)
- List of Slaves in Rockbridge County 1863, 2 items (Box 3)
- List of Insolvents, Rockbridge County 1863-1864 (Box 3)
- Papers concerning the settlement of Pattonsburg Mill and final distribution 1863-1876, 31 items (Box 3)
- Warrant for arrest of James Penn (free negro) 1864 February 1 and 27, 2 items (Box 3)
- N.G. Moore to John F. Greenlee 1864 May 13, ALS, 2 pp. w/env. (Box 3)
- C.N. Socher (?) to John F. Greenlee 1864 August 7, ALS, 1 p. (Box 3)
- Statement by Gov. William Smith re: exemption of John F. Greenlee from military service 1864 November 11, AMsS, 1 p. (Box 3)
- Receipts of Rockbridge County Allowances 1864, 6 items (Box 3)
- Miscellaneous receipts and papers, Rockbridge County 1864, ca. 35 items (Box 3)
- Various tax receipts of Rockbridge County 1864, ca. 100 items (Box 3)
- Estate papers of John S. Rowlison 1864, 7 items (Box 3)
- Papers relating to settlement of W.C. Gentry 1864-1866, 8 items (Box 3)
- Appointment of John F. Greenlee as Deputy Clerk of the Court of Rockbridge County 1865, 1 item (Box 3)
- Receipts of Rockbridge County Allowances 1865, 6 items (Box 3)
- Sale Bill of Personal Property belonging to the estate of Thomas G. Burks 1865, 1 item (Box 3)
- W.T. Bailey to [John F. Greenlee] [18]65 April 4, ALS, 1 p. (Box 3)
- W. Wood Greenlee to Cousin John[Greenlee] 1865 July 1, ALS, 1p. (Box 3)
- Miscellaneous receipts and papers, Rockbridge County 1865-1869, ca. 45 items (Box 3)
- M.H. Houston to John F. Greenlee 1866 April 4, ALS, 1 p. (Box 3)
- John T. James to John F. Greenlee 1866 October 10, ALS, 1 p. (Box 3)
- Papers concerning the settlement of the estate of Joseph Gilmore 1866-1867, ca. 35 items (Box 3)
- Claims due C.H. Anderson left with J.F. Greenlee for collection 1866-1868, 5 items (Box 3)
- Receipts of John F. Greenlee 1866-1869, ca. 35 items (Box 3)
- Letters of John F. Greenlee Executor of Joseph Gilmore in settlement of his estate 1867, 4 items (Box 3)
- E.S. Houston to John F. Greenlee ca. 1867 March 6, ALS, 1 p. (Box 3)
- Orlando Smith to Wm. F. Poague 1867 April 18, ALS, 1 p. w/env. (Box 3)
- Thomas R. Gilmore to [John] Greenlee [18]67 May 1(?), ALS, 1 p. (Box 3)
- Printed advertisements for dry goods, clothing, and a boarding house 1868 and n.d., 7 items (Box 3)
- William R. Greenlee to John [Greenlee] 1868 February 14, ALS, 2 pp. (Box 3)
- John W. Johnston to John F. Greenlee [18]68 February 24 and June 18, 2 ALS, 2 pp. and 1 p. (Box 3)
- Charles A. Davidson to John [Greenlee] 1868 March 7, ALS, 1 p. (Box 3)
- Douglas Frazar to John Greenlee 1868 May 12, ALS, 1 p., w/env. (Box 3)
- Leslie T. Hardy to John Greenlee 168 May 27, ALS, 1 p. (Box 3)
- Papers concerning settlement of the Estate of Joseph Gilmore 1868-1869, ca. 40 items (Box 3)
- Letters of John F. Greenlee Executor of Joseph Gilmore in settlement of his estate 1869, 25 items (Box 3)
- Articles of agreement of John F. Greenlee with William P. Barger for Landrum Debt 1869, 4 items (Box 3)
- John H.S.(?) Sandrum to [John] Greenlee 1869 March 11, ALS, 1 p. (Box 3)
- R.R. Houston to John F. Greenlee 1869 March 24, ALS, 1 p. (Box 3)
- L.E. Gilmell to [John] Greenlee [18]69 September 1, ALS, 2 pp. (Box 3)
- Letters of John F. Greenlee Executor of Joseph Gilmore in settlement of his estate 1870, 17 items (Box 3)
- Receipts of John F. Greenlee 1870-1871, 40 items (Box 3)
- Papers concerning settlement of estate of Joseph Gilmore 1870-1871, 10 items (Box 3)
- John W. Johnston to John F. Greenlee in regard to Pattonsburg Mills 1870-1873, 12 ALS, 2 env. (Box 3)
- Settlement of J.P. Moore with John F. Greenlee 1870-1877, 6 items (Box 3)
- Letters of John F. Greenlee Executor of Joseph Gilmore in settlement of his estate 1871, 5 items, 2 env. (Box 3)
- Papers concerning the settlement of the estate of Joseph Gilmore 1872, 17 items (Box 4)
- Letters of John F. Greenlee Executor of Joseph Gilmore in settlement of his estate 1872, 14 items (Box 4)
- Receipts of John F. Greenlee 1872, 33 items (Box 4)
- Miss Jennie A. Baird to John F. Greenlee 1872 January 24, ALS, 1 p. (Box 4)
- J.G. Steele to John F. Greenlee 1872 September 13, ALS, 1 p. (Box 4)
- Receipts of John F. Greenlee 1873, 23 items (Box 4)
- Letters of John F. Greenlee Executor of Joseph Gilmore in settlement of his estate 1873, 17 items (Box 4)
- R.D. Buford to John F. Greenlee 1873 February 3, ALS, 1 p. (Box 4)
- Lizzie Gilmore to [John F.] Greenlee [18]73 September 28, ALS, 2 pp. (Box 4)
- Papers concerning settlement of the estate of Joseph Gilmore 1873-1875, 5 items (Box 4)
- Receipts of John F. Greenlee 1874, 21 items (Box 4)
- Letters of John F. Greenlee Executor of Joseph Gilmore in settlement of his estate 1874, 5 items (Box 4)
- Notice of bankruptcy of Ed Echols sent to John F. Greenlee 1874 November, 1 postcard (Box 4)
- Greenlee Heirs vs. Virginia Military Institute 1874-1886, 3 items (Box 4)
- Receipts of John F. Greenlee 1875-1876, 38 items (Box 4)
- Letters of John F. Greenlee Executor of Joseph Gilmore in settlement of his estate 1875-1877, 8 items (Box 4)
- Statement of Bond, John F. Greenlee vs. C.H. Davidson 1875-1881, 4 items (Box 4)
- Statement of Bond, John F. Greenlee vs. C.H. Davidson, R.K. Dunlap and A.W. Moore 1875-1886, 6 items (Box 4)
- Papers concerning the settlement of the estate of Joseph Gilmore 1877, 6 items (Box 4)
- Thomas R. Gilmore to [John F.] Greenlee [18]77 March 28, 2 pp., w/env. (Box 4)
- J.R. Greenlee to John F. Greenlee 1877 May 19, ALS, 3 pp., w/env. (Box 4)
- J. R[ussell] Greenlee to Uncle John F. Greenlee 1877 June 25, ALS, 3 pp., w/env. (Box 4)
- Receipts of John F. Greenlee 1877-1878, 39 items (Box 4)
- J.S. Watson to John [F. Greenlee] [18]78 June 19, ALS, 1 p. (Box 4)
- Charles H. Anderson to J[ohn] F. Greenlee 1878 December 2 and 10, 2 ALS, 3 pp. and 1 p. w/env. (Box 4)
- Papers dealing with the settlement of Joseph Gilmore Estate 1878-1892, 23 items (Box 4)
- Receipts of John F. Greenlee 1879, 32 items (Box 4)
- Settlement of Bond of John W. Hamilton vs. Mary Jane Finley 1879, 4 pp. (Box 4)
- Francis P. Mullally to J[ohn] F. Greenlee 1879 April 30, ALS, 1 p. w/env (Box 4)
- R.K. Dunlap to John F. Greenlee 1879 May 24, ALS, 1 p. w/env. (Box 4)
- George J. Finlay to Uncle John [F. Greenlee] 1879 May 26 and September 29, 2 ALS, 2 pp. each 1 w/env. (Box 4)
- J.S. Watson to John [F. Greenlee] [18]79 October 2, ALS, 1 p., w/env. (Box 4)
- Receipts of John F. Greenlee 1880, 17 items (Box 4)
- J.S. Watson to John [F. Greenlee] [18]80 September 4, ALS, 1 p., w/env. (Box 4)
- Receipts of John F. Greenlee 1881, ca. 25 items (Box 4)
- Canceled checks of John F. Greenlee 1881, 16 items (Box 4)
- Statement and settlement of the Greenlee Ferry Estates 1881, 4 items (Box 4)
- Printed Funeral Notice of E.N. Davis 1881 January 15, 1 p., w/env. (Box 4)
- J.S. Watson to John [F. Greenlee] [18]81 May 4, ALS, 2 pp. (Box 4)
- S[amuel] R. Moore to John F. Greenlee 1881 December 10, ALS, 1 p., w/ env. (Box 4)
- F.H. Smith to John F. Greenlee 1881 December 22, ALS, 1 p., w/env. (Box 4)
- Receipts of John F. Greenlee 1882-1884, 18 items (Box 4)
- Receipts of John F. Greenlee 1885, 20 items (Box 4)
- List of Bonds Taxable for year 1886 1886 January 1, 1 item (Box 4)
- J.C. Paxton to John [F. Greenlee] 1886 December 17, ALS, 1 p. (Box 4)
- Receipts of John F. Greenlee 1886-1887, 29 items (Box 4)
- Letters of John F. Greenlee, Executor of Joseph Gilmore in settlement of Gilmore's estate 1886-1893 and n.d., 6 items (Box 4)
- Receipts of John F. Greenlee 1888-1890, 22 items (Box 4)
- Receipts of John F. Greenlee 1891-1893, 30 items (Box 4)
- Receipts of John F. Greenlee 1894, 19 items (Box 4)
- Receipts of John F. Greenlee 1895, 28 items (Box 4)
- Receipts of John F. Greenlee 1896, 23 items (Box 4)
- John F. Greenlee's Receipts 1897-1898, 30 items (Box 4)
- Marshall T. Levey to Dear Banker, used to wrap account papers of John F. Greenlee 1912 summer, TLS form letter, 1 p. (Box 4)
- List of Soldiers, Wives and Children, Rockbridge County n.d., 1 item (Box 4)
- Miscellaneous Papers, Rockbridge County n.d., ca. 50 items (Box 4)